libertyinsurance.ie 2012-06-23

# Liberty Insurance Security and Privacy Statement | Liberty Insurance Ireland

## Data Protection Statement: Liberty Insurance

Liberty Insurance Limited is the registered data controller in relation to personal information held about you for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts. By visiting the Liberty Insurance website, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. You should show this notice to anyone who may be covered by your insurance policy with Liberty Insurance.

We will use the information you provide to manage and administer your insurance policy and for underwriting, claims handling and fraud prevention purposes. In order to provide you with products and services this information will be held in our data systems or by our agents or subcontractors.

We may check the information you provide against other information available to the public (such as the edited electoral roll, court judgments, bankruptcy or repossessions). We may exchange information with other insurers either directly or through people acting for the insurer (such as Loss Adjusters or Private Investigators), and, where we are entitled to do so under the Data Protection Acts, the Garda Síochána, Police Service or any person authorised by law to access customer records.

It may be necessary for us to collect sensitive data (such as medical conditions or criminal convictions) relating to you and others named on the insurance policy. Please get consent from the other people named on your policy before sharing their sensitive information with us. By proceeding with this contract you will signify your explicit consent to such information being processed by us or our agents or other insurers for any of the purposes outlined above.

We may pass information about you and your claims history to our agents and service providers, members of the Liberty Mutual Insurance, other insurers and their agents, any agent acting for you, and to recognised trade, governing, and regulatory bodies we are a member of or which we are governed by. We may disclose information about you to anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our arrangements with you.

We share and exchange information with the Insurance Link database, run by the Irish Insurance Federation. The aim is to help us prevent fraudulent claims. Under the conditions of your policy, you must tell us about any incident (such as an accident, theft, fire or water damage) which may or may not give rise to a claim. When a claim is settled, we will pass information about it to this register. We may use the information you provide to get information from the National Vehicle and Driver File held by the Department of Transport.

We may also transfer your information to other countries on the basis that anyone to whom we pass it provides an adequate level of protection.

All incoming and outgoing telephone conversations may be recorded and monitored for training, quality and fact verification purposes.

### Other Information

We would like to keep you informed about the products and services we provide. If you would prefer not to receive this information from us, and have not previously advised us of this, please let us know when you contact us. Your information may also be used for these purposes after your policy has lapsed.

We may contact you with a reminder that your policy is due for renewal. It is our policy to only take instructions to change a policy from the policyholder, your spouse, civil partner, or parent. In some cases we may also deal with other people who call on your behalf with your consent. If you prefer that we only deal with you, please let us know.

You have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you by writing to our Customer Services Manager and enclosing a cheque for €6.35. You may also request the amendment or deletion of any information we hold about you and we will make all reasonable efforts to update our records if it is deemed appropriate. 

### Use of Liberty Insurance website

We may also record additional information on the webpages you have visited and the contents of those webpages, any information you input, your referring URL or IP address, your time of visit and related session information, your requested page, web browser type, USR agent, status of request (successful reply), cookies, number of bytes in the response, and query string and any information or technical detail your browser is sending to us. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. We use this information to better understand website usage in the aggregate so that we know what areas of our website users prefer. This information is stored in log files and is used for statistical reporting and in limited circumstances to prevent fraudulent claims.

We may collect basic information using cookies about the way you have used the site. We may also occasionally use cookies to recognise you as a site user and to personalise your visit. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser so that you will not receive cookies and you can delete existing cookies from your browser. However, you may find that some parts of the site will not function properly if you refuse cookies. This information will be used to improve the content of our website and help us provide you with a better experience and will not be shared with any third party. 

### Security

We take our security responsibilities seriously, employing the most appropriate physical and technical measures, including staff training and awareness. We review our security measures and procedures regularly.

Any area of our site that is used to capture your personal information or payment details will always be in a secure session using 128-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption, which is the industry standard. For some products, website customers will have the opportunity to register an email address and password.

### Fraudulent Emails Warning

Liberty Insurance will never contact you by email to request an update of your personal or private information. If you receive any such emails please contact us by telephone immediately.

### Change to Statement

We may occasionally update this privacy statement. Therefore we would suggest you periodically review this statement to stay informed about how we are meeting our obligations under the Data Protection Acts. Your continual use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.
